<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!DOCTYPE document SYSTEM "./dtd/document-v10.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Jesktop Documentation</title>
    <subtitle>Class Diagrams</subtitle>
    <authors>
      <person id="WB" name="William Beebe" email="whbeebe@earthlink.net"/>
      <person id="PH" name="Paul Hammant" email="Paul_Hammant@yahoo.com"/>
    </authors>
    <notice>
      Jesktop documentation is under construction.  Everything you
      can find outside this page is to be considered obsolete.
    </notice>
  </header>
  <body>
    <s1 title="Introduction">
      <p>     
	These class diagrams show various parts of the Jesktop system.  A complete diagram would be too messy to show, so sections are shown here.
      </p> 
    </s1>
    <s1 title="Class Diagrams">
    <s2 title="Kernel">    
      <figure src="images/classdiag_kernel.gif" alt="Kernel Class Diagram"/>
      <p>           
	This diagram shows the Kernel as an abstract class <em>DesktopKernel</em> and it's implementation <em>DesktopKernelImpl</em>.  Also shown are <em>AppLauncher</em>, <em>AppInstaller</em> and <em>ImageRepository</em> with their implementations.  These are parts of the Kernel really but have been moved out of the Kernel for reasons of modularity.
      </p> 	  
    </s2>    
    <s2 title="Frimble plus FrimbleDemo">    
      <figure src="images/classdiag_frimble.gif" alt="Frimble Class Diagram"/>
      <p>           
	This diagram shows the <em>Frimble</em> abstract class and it's two final extensions <em>JFrameFrimble</em> and <em>JInternalFrameFrimble</em>.  Also shown are <em>FrimbleAware</em> (the interface that some applications will implement) and <em>FrimbleEvent</em>, <em>FrimbleListener</em> &amp; <em>FrimbleAdapter</em> (the event handling helper classes).  Lastly <em>FrimbleDemo</em> shows an app that implements <em>FrimbleAware</em>.
      </p> 	  
    </s2>
    <s2 title="Example Window Managers">    
      <figure src="images/classdiag_windowmanagers.gif" alt="Window Managers Class Diagram"/>
      <p>           
	Very much a work in progress, this diagram shows the test implementations of the <em>WindowManager</em> interface.  All are working to various degrees, but only <em>WindozeWindowManager</em> is being polished.  At some point the useful common code will be rolled in to a new class called <em>AbstractWindowManager</em> and the other window managers (that still have merit) moved to separate packages.
      </p> 	  
    </s2>    
    </s1>
   </body>   
  <footer>
    <legal>
      Copyright (c) @year@ The Jesktop Project All rights reserved.
    </legal>
  </footer>
</document>
