<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!DOCTYPE document SYSTEM "./dtd/document-v10.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Jesktop Documentation</title>
    <subtitle>Skins</subtitle>
    <authors>
      <person id="WB" name="William Beebe" email="whbeebe@earthlink.net"/>
      <person id="PH" name="Paul Hammant" email="Paul_Hammant@yahoo.com"/>
    </authors>
    <notice>
      Jesktop documentation is under construction.  Everything you
      can find outside this page is to be considered obsolete.
    </notice>
  </header>
  <body>
    <s1 title="Overview">
      <p>
        Jesktop supports different skins for the decoration of frames, fonts, colors and iconography.
      </p>
    </s1>
    <s1 title="Detailed">
      <p>
        By Skin we mean the decoration that surrounds individual frames, the style and colors of widgets. We allow skin changing through applications that implement a Decorator interface.  These applications will be Jesktop only (not dual mode), but the toolkits they use might be quite independent of Jesktop. At this stage we have the following:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Default Decorator.  Metal Look and Feel and small icons for application frames.
        </li>
        <li>
          Test Decorator.  Choice of Metal or Motif look and feel, Choice of small of Big icons for application frames.  <link href="http://www.jesktop.net">See www.jesktop.net</link>
        </li>
        <li>
          OYOAHA Decorator.  Multiple choices of look and feel.  The license for this is a bit unclear and Jesktop uses the compiled jar.  <link href="http://www.jesktop.net">See www.jesktop.net</link> and <link href="http://www.oyoaha.com">www.oyoaha.com</link>
        </li>
        <li>
          Skin look and feel Decorator.  Again, multiple choices of look and feel.  The license for this is Apache-alike.  <link href="http://www.jesktop.net">See www.jesktop.net</link> and <link href="http://www.l2fprod.com">www.l2fprod.com</link>.  Mac, Windows, Beos, Aqua and XP-Luna look and feels are provided.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </s1>
  </body>
  <footer>
    <legal>
      Copyright (c) @year@ The Jesktop Project All rights reserved.
    </legal>
  </footer>
</document>
