<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!DOCTYPE document SYSTEM "./dtd/document-v10.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Jesktop Documentation</title>
    <subtitle>Where Jesktop is heading</subtitle>
    <authors>
      <person id="WB" name="William Beebe" email="whbeebe@earthlink.net"/>
      <person id="PH" name="Paul Hammant" email="Paul_Hammant@yahoo.com"/>
    </authors>
    <notice>
      Jesktop documentation is under construction.  Everything you
      can find outside this page is to be considered obsolete.
    </notice>
  </header>
  <body>
    <s1 title="The future">
      <p>     
	The development of Jesktop is closely mirroring that of Avalon.  Avalon
	will gain server blocks (http, smtp, pop3 imap, dns, nntp ++++).  At the
	same time Jesktop will gain applications too. the majority of those will
	not be from the Jesktop team but from the other formerly unrelated
	projects.  These teams hopefully will make their apps dual mode -
	capable of running from the command line and inside Jesktop.
      </p>	
      <p>     
	We also see ourselves extending the functionality of the desktop
	itself. All of these features are planned (some will rely on
	improvements to Avalon).      
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Multi lingual desktop.
        </li>
        <li>
          User login and log out
        </li>
        <li>
          Improved Mime type support - Mime type aware panels will be usable in The File browser and web browser
        </li>
        <li>
        New Window Managers.
	  - Mac, Next, Amiga, Beos....

        </li>
        <li>
          Hot Window Manager changing (just like KDE, Gnome etc. under linux) - log off, choose new WM, log in.
        </li>
        <li>
          Patching of AWT usage to Swing - this will allow Java 1 applet support without the well known "heavyweight component in lightweight container" feature/bug.
        </li>
        <li>
	  Support for Tear-off Applets - In your browser, choose "tear-off applet" while mouse is over applet in web page  - this will install that applet as an app, and not require that you are subsequently connected to the internet to use it.        
        </li>
        <li>
	  Remote usage, Connect via an remote stub application, applet, or remote Java Web Start (TM) app.       
        </li>
        <li>
 	  Better control of window positions and size at launch.        
        </li>
        <li>
	  More Shells.  - Ant may well be improved soon so that all of its commands can be invoked from a command line type console inside Jesktop. - we will also have commands that are Avalon and Jesktop specific e.g. "Shutdown".      
        </li>
        <li>	  
          Security polices for Jars. - things like clock that require no special resources, can run inside a sandbox. - other applications can ask for permission to read/write to specific directories and other permissions.
        </li>        
      </ul>           
    </s1>
  </body>
  <footer>
    <legal>
      Copyright (c) @year@ The Jesktop Project All rights reserved.
    </legal>
  </footer>
</document>
